David M Brown Junior Full Stack Developer

davidbtechrev@gmail.com • +0044 7896 711 975 • Greater Manchester https://github.com/Cloud-Monkey • linkedin.com/in/daveb-code

Personal Summary

A Junior Software Developer, a Code Institute and a Northcoders Software Development bootcamp graduate. My technical expertise includes JavaScript, Python, HTML, CSS, React and Django. Experience with AWS through the In4.0 Group, a Cloud Practitioner Certificate and a solid foundation in test driven development, pair programming, React, Django and Bootstrap frameworks. Through customer service, sales and gaming industry roles, I gained excellent collaborative, communicative, and creative problem-solving skills. I am enthused to enter the tech industry and contribute to a team or organisation, where I can continue to learn.

Education

June 2024—Sept 2024 Diploma in Full Stack Software Development

Code Institute - Dublin, Ireland

Feb 2023–May 2023 Northcoders Full Stack Software Development Bootcamp

NorthCoders - Manchester Technology Centre, UK

Feb 2021-May 2021 In4.0 Group AWS Cloud Practitioner – AWS re/Start

In4.0 Group - Salford, UK

Sept 2017-June 2019 Cert HE BSc(Hons) Sports Rehabilitation

University of Bolton - Bolton, UK

Sept 2016-July 2017 Access to Health and Physiotherapy

The Manchester College - Manchester, UK

Technical Skill Set

Technologies: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, Python, Express.Js, Jest Databases: Google Firebase, MongoDB, MySQL, Postgres

Frameworks: React.Js, Django, Bootstrap

Version Control: Git/Github

Portfolio projects

Park Find and Remind - Parking App which can remember your parking spot, set a timer and will guide you
back to your space via GPS and a map Technologies Used - React Native.Js, Expo, Google Firebase, TomTom
Maps API, JavaScript.

GitHub - https://github.com/differently-wired/park-finder

2. NC Games Vapour - Frontend React App games website that allows users to review and comment on games and like/dislike peoples comments or reviews. Technologies Used - React. Js, Postgres , CSS, JavaScript, Jest.

GitHub - https://github.com/Cloud-Monkey/fe-NC-Games-Vapour

- **3.** NC Games Vapour Backend REST API to allow GET, POST, PATCH, DELETE from a database of reviews, user profiles and comments for a games website React Frontend. **Technologies Used** Express.Js, JavaScript, Postgres DB, SQL, Jest.
 - GitHub https://github.com/Cloud-Monkey/be-NC-Games-Vapour
- **4. TUCUM Capoeira -** Website for a Capoeira club showcasing a gallery of images, Brazilian culture, Capoeira, details for classes and social media links. **Technologies Used** HTML5, CSS with Bootstrap, JavaScript.
 - GitHub https://github.com/Cloud-Monkey/TUCUM-capoeira
- **5. Portfolio -** Personal online portfolio showcasing personal development projects. **Technologies Used** React.Js, HTML5, CSS, JavaScript.
 - GitHub https://github.com/Cloud-Monkey/reactversionportfolio

Work Experience

July 2023-Feb 2024

Sales Consultant, Natuzzi Editions

Natuzzi, Manchester, UK

- Applied sales techniques to convert telephone or face-to-face interactions into sales.
- Greeted customers in a friendly and polite manner in-line with company standards.
- Matched customers with the ideal products and services, through effective questioning.
- Demonstrated in-depth knowledge of products and manufacturers to meet clients needs.
- 360 degree sales tasks including lead generation, follow up and CRM management.
- Worked towards sales targets and deadlines.

Oct 2019-Dec 2022

Gaming Supervisor, Genting International

Genting, Manchester, UK

- Explained house rules, such as game rules and betting limits to customers.
- Dealt and supervised casino games such as American roulette, Blackjack, Punto Banco, Three-card poker, Texas Hold-em poker and numerous other card variations which are no longer available.
- Exchanges and Verified currency, calculated payable odds to pay winning bets.
- Resolved guest complaints quickly, effectively and tactfully, developing extensive problem solving skills.
- Retained premium members through excellent customer service.
- Implemented established rules and secure procedures of each specific game to a high standard.
- Responsibility for protecting company assets, balancing assets regularly, while maintaining policy and gaming law thresholds, working logically and methodically.

Inspector, Genting International

Manchester235, Manchester, UK

- Explained house rules, such as game rules and betting limits to customers.
- Dealt and supervised casino games such as American roulette, Blackjack, Punto Banco, Three-card poker, Texas Hold-em poker and numerous other card variations which are no longer available.
- Exchanges and Verified currency, calculated payable odds to pay winning bets.
- Resolved guest complaints quickly, effectively and tactfully.
- Retained premium members through excellent customer service.
- Implemented established rules and secure procedures of each specific game to a high standard.
- Responsibility for protecting company assets, balancing assets regularly, while maintaining policy and gaming law thresholds.

Certifications

- NorthCoders Full Stack Software Development Course (16 Weeks, 35 Hours per week)
- Code Institute Full Stack Software Development (16 Weeks, 35 Hours per week)
- AWS Cloud Practitioner AWS ReStart (12 Weeks, 35 Hour per week)
- Coders Guild Get Hired as a Junior/Apprentice Developer (12 Weeks)

<u>Tech Interests/Additional Information</u>

- Participation in Code Institute Hackathon: Frontend HTML CSS I was the scrum master on this collaborative project and took responsibility for agile project management.
- Participation in Softwire Group: A11y Accessibility workshop Gained significant understanding of the needs of visually impaired users, the use of screen reader technology and Aria labels.
- I like to train my JavaScript logic ability daily on Codewars katas, where I have attained 4th kyu rank.
- I build custom PCs which I sell privately and I enjoy performing hardware maintenance and modification.
- I refurbish Macs and use unsupported OS patchers as a way of reducing E waste.
- In my spare time I practise Yoga and Capoeira for health and social.
- I enjoy different languages and I have learnt to speak some Mandarin and Portuguese.